



I like to play with data and help communicate the stories it tells using nifty visualizations. I'm trained in GIS and cartography, which gave me a foundation in web design and programming. My career goal is to use my skills in the context of infectious disease research and communication.

For additional information, please check out my website and resumap.

Skills

WEB DESIGN PROGRAMMING GIS DATA ANALYSIS • • 0 HTML5 **ArcGIS** Python • 0 0 QGIS SAS • 0 0 CSS Java • 0 0 Carto JavaScript • Leaflet • • o Bootstrap • D3.is

Education

Master of Public Health: Epidemiology of Microbial Diseases

Yale University, expected 2019

Concentration: Public Health Modeling

Summer Internship: Spatial Analysis of Opioid Deaths at the CT Office of the Chief Medical Examiner

Master of Science: GIS and Web Map Programming

University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2018

Practicum: Development of Antimicrobial Resistance Web Map

Coursework: Geospatial statistics, Java development, Android application development,

and building PostgreSQL databases.

Graduate Certificate: Geographic Information Systems

University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2017

Capstone: Prototype of AMR Visualizer using JavaScript and D3.js

Coursework: Python data management, ArcGIS analysis, and cartographic principles.

Bachelor of Arts: International Studies, Political Science, Languages & Cultures of Asia

University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2013

Concentration: Global Health

Study Abroad: Pune, India during Summer 2013 at Fergusson College, where I interned at Parvati Swayamrojgar Yojana, a microfinance organization.

Experience

Student Cartographer Madison, WI | November 2016 - March 2018

University of Wisconsin-Madison School of Pharmacy

I developed an interactive web map of antibiotic resistance in Wisconsin using Carto, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, and SQL. The map is intended to further antibiotic stewardship by helping prescribers more easily access antibiogram data while revealing how resistance varies spatially. Check it out right here.

Web Designer and Cartographer Madison, WI | May 2016 - May 2017

University of Wisconsin-Madison Cartography Lab

Using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap, I assisted the lab with front-end web design to develop a searchable database of their cartographic research and projects.

GIS Technician Madison, WI | February 2016 - July 2017

University of Wisconsin-Madison Forest Ecosystem and Landscape Ecology Lab
I digitized hand-drawn landuse maps of Wisconsin townships by
georeferencing TIFs, cutting polyons using a Wacom tablet, and assigning
attributes to each new polygon in ArcGIS.

Student Cartographer Madison, WI | August 2015 - August 2016

Wisconsin Office of Rural Health

I assisted the resident epidemiologist with her GIS-intensive projects. For example, I helped in the initial stages of creating an original rurality index based on population density and adjacency to metro areas. Additionally, I created step-by-step guides for using ArcGIS, Adobe Illustrator, and CartoDB for use by office staff.

Volunteering

Contributing Writer Remote Position | March 2013 - Present

GenTwenty, an online magazine for twentysometings

I compose 1000+ word original articles for an online magazine for millennials. My writing, storytelling, and editing skills have been an integral part of *GenTwenty*'s growth from a startup blog to an online magazine with 100.000+ page views per month and a published book.

Infectious Disease Mapping Intern Remote Position | August 2016 - August 2017 Department of State via the Virtual Student Foreign Service

I led a mapping competition at UW-Madison as part of the U.S. State Department's goal to more effectively visualize health objectives related to the Global Health Security Agenda. My role included providing technical GIS support and cartographic consultation for participants, as well as campus outreach and student recruitment.